<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue-Prince on My not-quite-daily notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/blue-prince/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blue-Prince on My not-quite-daily notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:07:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/blue-prince/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blue Prince</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/06/blue-prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/06/blue-prince/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/ob/posts/attachments/IMG_7504.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;my Blue Prince notebook. it&amp;rsquo;s a lovely reflective blue and silver in person&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/06/clearly-not-out-of-my-way-enough/&#34;&gt;at one point &lt;/a&gt; that I had beaten &lt;em&gt;Blue Prince&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; inasmuch as one can truly believe they have fully plumbed the depths of the bottomless puzzle pool that is &lt;em&gt;Blue Prince,&lt;/em&gt; which at this point I fully believe I have done. But did I like the game?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, an anecdote: a few weeks ago now I was a guest on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blizzardwatch.com/2025/06/20/blizzard-watch-podcast-lorewalking-timewalking-delves-oh/&#34;&gt;the Blizzard Watch Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, and we asked editor-in-chief Liz if &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; liked &lt;em&gt;Blue Prince.&lt;/em&gt; We then poked fun at it later because she hemmed and hawed about the game, talked about a number of things she did or didn&amp;rsquo;t like, discussed the weirdness and the puzzles and the worldbuilding and whether or not things like the letter I missing from every keyboard matters, and never got around to actually saying whether or not she liked the game. This is, I am finding, something of a common refrain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clearly not out of my way enough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/06/clearly-not-out-of-my-way-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/06/clearly-not-out-of-my-way-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clearly a blogging system that got mostly out of my way so I could focus on blogging wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite good enough. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite help that I broke my setup with Windows for a bit &amp;ndash; the newest version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/&#34;&gt;Quartz&lt;/a&gt; requires a newer version of Node.js than we were using for work, so I ended up switching back to using &lt;a href=&#34;https://zone-builder.neocities.org&#34;&gt;Zoner&lt;/a&gt;, which has been a trip. That also means actual new posts aren&amp;rsquo;t getting posted for a bit because I&amp;rsquo;m not just reinventing the wheel, I&amp;rsquo;m finding entirely new ways to reinvent the reinventing machine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
