<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Switch-2 on My not-quite-daily notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/switch-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Switch-2 on My not-quite-daily notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 19:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/switch-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switch 2 direct quick thoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/04/switch-2-direct-quick-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 10:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/04/switch-2-direct-quick-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My coworker asked me for my thoughts on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VrTVeYm4iIM&#34;&gt;Nintendo Switch 2 Direct&lt;/a&gt;. Since he was in a meeting, I took notes. And since I took notes, here they are.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mario Kart World&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New Mario Kart was the one thing I figured was guaranteed since MK 8 was 11 years old&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Looks really nice - feels like PS4-era graphics?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Like the idea of a circuit as one continuous race&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Free roam is a cute feature&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Only saw 1 new racer but I think it was one of the cows from Moo Moo Meadows. lol&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hardware features&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GameChat&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Did not call the C button being for game chat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nintendo just straight up lifting Discord&amp;rsquo;s voice UI is a bold choice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GameShare&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Welcome back, one of the best features of the DS!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Online play via GameShare is wild, though&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hardware details&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1080p up to 120 fps, with 4K docked, makes me more certain this is basically a PS4&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really hoping magnetic joycons feel less flimsy/fragile when attached and used in handheld mode compared to the rails&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No mention of the joysticks being Hall Effect; hopefully they&amp;rsquo;ve fixed the drift issue&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Two charging ports is smart. More handhelds should do this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enhanced games&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Super Mario Party Jamboree: Neat and all but this is still my least favorite Mario Party in a while&amp;hellip;. it&amp;rsquo;s so sloooooow&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Switch Zeldas: Very cool to see. Don&amp;rsquo;t think I necessarily need to play these again, but they look nice. The phone thing is a fun gimmick, but at least Nintendo is thinking about stuff like that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kirby and the Forgotten Land: This is basically DLC, right? Fun game but man this was WAY too hard at points for a Kirby game&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Metroid Prime 4: Switch 2 Edition: This is how I&amp;rsquo;ll probably wait to play this. Kinda wild to see Nintendo offering graphical settings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pokemon Legends Z-A: See, now Nintendo is making problems for me: I want to play this game but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to buy it once and then buy the upgrade pack too to play it on Switch 2.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mouse Mode games: Give me Mario Paint 2 or give me death&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third party games&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Elden Ring: Well, didn&amp;rsquo;t see THAT coming. &amp;ldquo;Tarnished Edition&amp;rdquo; is right; gameplay looking a little rough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hades II: Not surprised, and this&amp;rsquo;ll be great. Hades still probably the most-played game on my original Switch. However, I already have it on Steam&amp;hellip;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Street Fighter 6: Local wireless and exclusive game modes, but no mention of allowing the Switch into the current online play. Pass&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daemon x Machina 2: Day 1 purchase for me, no questions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Split Fiction: Already playing this! It&amp;rsquo;s actually a great couch co-op game, my wife loves it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sports: zzzzz&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hogwarts Legacy: didn&amp;rsquo;t play it before, not gonna play it now either&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;THPS 3+4: Yeah, probably a day 1 purchase for this too&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hitman World of Assassination: I haven&amp;rsquo;t played this Hitman game, but in general modern Hitman games are really fun. A James Bond crossover is interesting. Playing on Goldeneye nostalgia?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bravely Default HD: I have a funny comment about this that is also a story spoiler so if you haven&amp;rsquo;t played it I&amp;rsquo;m just gonna say: Bravely Default is very fun and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably get this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yakuza 0: I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna buy it and play it again but Yakuza 0 is one of the best games I&amp;rsquo;ve ever played, happy to see it on Switch. Expect the rest of the series to follow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment: it might be nice to have a Hyrule Warriors that doesn&amp;rsquo;t run like garbage (a thing we haven&amp;rsquo;t had since the Wii U, of all things). I&amp;rsquo;ll end up picking this up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GameCube library on Switch Online membership: this just continues to be worth the money. F-Zero GX definitely the one I&amp;rsquo;m most interested to play right off the bat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deltarune: This another one of those &amp;ldquo;not surprised to see it on Switch, happy to see it on Switch, but I already have it on Steam&amp;rdquo; moments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Borderlands 4: They&amp;rsquo;re still making these? Sure, why not. Borderlands is fun.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Civilization VII: If they fix the problems the PC version has, I might pick this up, but the PC one launched in really sad shape for a premium AAA title.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Survival Kids: Okay, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely funny to see a Konami franchise last seen on the Game Boy Color in like 1999 come back for the Switch 2.  This may or may not be good, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably hold off on picking it up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enter the Gungeon 2: This should be extremely good &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; it runs well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starseeker: I don&amp;rsquo;t know what this is, and the animation looks a little rough, but it gives me No Man&amp;rsquo;s Sky vibes, so might be worth a look.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 Ultimate Edition: Is this finally what gets me to play CP2077? Guess we&amp;rsquo;ll find out.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FF7 Remake Intergrade: I had a lot of fun with Remake after adjusting my expectations. This is pretty cool to see on a Nintendo platform again.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The lightning round at the end (most of these I had no opinion on other than &amp;ldquo;that looks cool&amp;rdquo;):&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S: Glad to see this series finally getting more consistent US localizations. Another good couch game.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Star Wars Outlaws: Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m underselling the Switch 2&amp;rsquo;s hardware capabilities. 😂&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grimdark Pac-man and Raidou Remastered are also on my to-buy list&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Professor Layton and the New World of Steam: Wait, that&amp;rsquo;s not a Switch 2 game, that&amp;rsquo;s coming out THIS year for Switch 1. (And I&amp;rsquo;ll probably get it.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Duskbloods: Okay, Nintendo scoring a Fromsoft exclusive is &lt;em&gt;huge.&lt;/em&gt; A lot of people who have been begging Sony for a new Bloodborne for years are gonna love this: this feels like it&amp;rsquo;s trying to evoke Bloodborne without explicitly being set in that universe. But a multiplatyer vampire extraction shooter? No thanks.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/ob/posts/attachments/bafkreihgzwyd4zqs6hbtdk6tbyrxpgdbnquijiaeld4kgmwol5krcncdxu@jpeg.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Run! It&amp;rsquo;s Bloodborne!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;It looks like Bloodborne but due to international copyright laws - it&amp;rsquo;s not.&amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kirby Air Riders: I cannot imagine this is the game a lot of people wanted from Masahiro Sakurai, but man, Kirby Air Ride was fun. I&amp;rsquo;ll play this for sure. (Did he really have to say that the first one came out on the Gamecube over 20 years ago though?? My bones hurt.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Donkey Kong Bananza: I honestly cannot believe it took this long to get Donkey Kong in a 3D platformer? With what looks like &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; destructible environments, too. This looks extremely fun.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The price: $449.99 might be a little rich for my blood at this point, that&amp;rsquo;s my only issue. Nintendo very rarely has anything stay exclusive except for first-party games, and $450 is approaching the point of a PC handheld.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
